Finding Aid for the Kenneth Macgowan Papers LSC.0887
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Manuscripts
  - Correspondence and Ephemera
    - Correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan and various persons re Behind the screen.... v.p., 1935-1963.; Approximately 105 items. Holograph and typescript. Arranged alphabetically, A - H. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Breen Joseph I., 3 items. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - The British film institute. London., 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Cinerama, Incorporated. New York., 14 items. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Cooper, Merian C., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Corlin, R.M., 4 items. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Cornwell-Clyne, A., 3 items. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Council of Motion Picture Organizations, Incorporated. New York., 4 items. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - de Forest, Lee., 3 items. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Deutsches institut für filmkunde E.V., 3 items. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Dittmar, Peter., 5 items. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - The Dramatists Guild of the Authors League of America, Incorporated. New York., 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Dufay limited. England., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Eastman, George., 1 item (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Editions Bernard Grasset. Paris., 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - The Elmer Belt Library of Vinciana., 4 items. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - The film daily. New York., 4 items. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Fulton, A.R., 3 items. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - George Eastman house, publishers, New York., 11 items. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Gordon, Jay E., 3 items. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Grand Chancellerie de la legion d'honneur., 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Harrison's reports. New York., 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Healey, Giles., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Hodkinson, William W., 6 items. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Horizon. New York., 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Horner, Harry., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan and various persons re Behind the screen.... continued. v.p., 1954-1963.; Approximately 110 items. Holograph and typescript. Arranged alphabetically, I - O. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - International photographers of the motion picture industries. Hollywood, California., 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Jones, Dorothy B., 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Jordan, Mildred., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Killiam, Paul., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Knight, Arthur., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Kuiper, John B., 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - La Grande, Frank., 9 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Lasky, Jesse L., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Levine, David., 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Leyda, Jay., 6 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Life. New York., 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Lindgren, Ernest., 8 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Lonzo, Michael., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Loucks and Norling studios, Incorporated. New York., 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - McDonald, Gerald D., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Matthews, Glenn E., 9 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Mayer, Arthur L., 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Mayer, Louis B., 3 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Minnesota mining and manufacturing company. Saint Paul, Minnesota., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Mitchell, George J. Jr., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Morrison, Jack., 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Motion picture association of America, Incorporated. New York., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Museum of modern art. New York., 29 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - National film archive; a division of the British film institute. London., 5 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Newhall, Beaumont., 7 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - The New York public library., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - The New York Times., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Osterreichische gesellschaft für filmwissenschaft und filmwirtschaft. Wien, Austria., 4 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan and various persons re Behind the screen.... v.p., 1954-1963.; Approximately 80 items. Typescript (some carbon). Arranged alphabetically, P - T. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Paramount pictures corporation. Hollywood., 10 items. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Polaroid corporation. Cambridge, Massachusetts., 3 items. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Prouse, Derek., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Quigley publishing company, Incorporated. New York., 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Radio city music hall. New York., 5 items. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Raibaud, Paul., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Roxy enterprises corporation. New York., 4 items. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Ryder sound services, Incorporated. Hollywood., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Sadoul, George., 5 items. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Screen actors guild. Hollywood., 3 items. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Selznick, David O., 3 items. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Sheaffer, Louis., 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Society of motion picture and television engineers. New York., 8 items. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Sperling, Milton., 5 items. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Stern, Seymour., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Technicolor corporation. Hollywood., 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Tessonneau, Rémy., 5 items. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Thomas Alva Edison foundation, Incorporated. West Orange, New Jersey., 4 items. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - The times-picayune publishing company. New Orleans, Louisiana., 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Twentieth century-fox film corporation. New York., 23 items. (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan and various persons re Behind the screen.... v.p., 1954-1963.; Approximately 35 items. Typescript (some carbon). Arranged alphabetically, U - Z. (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - United States department of commerce. Washington, D.C., 3 items. (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - United States department of interior. Edison laboratory national monument. Orange, New Jersey., 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - United States department of labor. Washington, D.C., 3 items. (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Variety. New York., 7 items. (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Vivié, Jean., 13 items. (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Walker, Ralph., 4 items. (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Walt Disney productions. Burbank, California., 3 items. (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Warner brothers pictures, Incorporated. Burbank, California., 3 items. (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence re Behind the screen.... consisting of unidentified letters, notes, drafts, and miscellaneous carbon copies. v.p., v.d.; Approximately 50 items. Typescript and some holograph. (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan and the Dell Publishing Company, Incorporated. re Behind the screen.... v.p., 1960-1963.; 91 items. Typescript (some carbon). (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan and Gordon Henricks re Behind the screen.... v.p., 1957-1963.; Approximately 65 items, plus numerous extra notes. Holograph and typescript. (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan and Nannine Joseph re Behind the screen.... v.p., 1955-1961.; 20 items. Typescript (some carbon). (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan and Arthur Krows re Behind the screen.... v.p., 1954-1955.; 24 items. Typescript (some carbon). (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan and Clark Wilkinson re Behind the screen.... v.p., 1957.; 7 items. Typescript (few carbon). (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Articles included in research material for Behind the screen.... Los Angeles, 1946 and 1949.; 6 items. (Box 21, Folder 11)
      Included are typescripts and printed copies.
      One article appeared in Script, February 1949, and another in the Hollywood Quarterly, vol.2 no.1, October 1946.
    - --- Articles included in research material for Behind the screen.... v.p., v.d.; 5 items. Typescript (carbon). (Box 21, Folder 12)
      The articles are arranged alphabetically. Copies of several of the articles are also found elsewhere in the collection.
    - --- Printed articles included in research material for Behind the screen.... v.p., v.d.; 10 items. (Box 21, Folder 13)
      The articles have been clipped from various periodicals and are chronologically arranged.
  - Manuscripts Written by Authors other than Kenneth Macgowan. v.p., v.d.
    - [A - H], [7 items] Typescript (mostly carbon).
      Arranged according to author.
      The Articles Are Listed as Follows:
      - Coward, Noel - The marquis; a comedy in three acts. n.p., n.d.; 132 leaves. Typescript (carbon). (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Dombrow, Sinclair - Clown of god, by Hugo Wolfgand Philipp, translated by Sinclair Dombrow. n.p., 9 leaves. Typescript. A note is attatched. (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Eliot, Samuel A Jr. - [Untitled article on the Little theater in Indianapolis] n.p., 4 leaves. Typescript with inked-in corrections. (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Forgy, Howell Maurice - A definition of plot for the playwright. [Los Angeles], n.d.; 12 leaves. Typescript (carbon). (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Handelman, Norman - Huge: a comic tragedy. n.p., 2 leaves. Typescript. (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Hoffenstein, Samuel - Orpheus, act I. n.p., n.d.; 26 leaves. Typescript. (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Farley, David - Sweet silver trumpets. Los Angeles, June 1958.; Approximately 132 leaves. Typescript (photocopy). (Box 22, Folder 2)
        Included is a letter from David Farley to Mr. Macgowan. Apparently, Mr. Farley was a student of Mr. Macgowan at one time.
    - [I - Z], 7 items. Typescript (mostly carbon).
      Included are a few letters.
      The Articles Are Arranged Alphabetically According to Author, I - Z, Plus Anonymous. They Are Listed as Follows:
      - Muensterberg, Hugo - The photoplay; a psychological study. London, 1916.; 5 leaves. Typescript (carbon). (Box 22, Folder 3)
        This consists of direct quotations cited from the book, with page no.indicated.
      - Seldes, Gilbert - Correspondence and manuscript material. v.p., v.d.; Approximately 47 leaves. Typescript (some carbon). (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Anonymous., (The material is arranged alphabetically). (Box 22, Folder 3)
        - The gardner's dog, by Jeanne? [Los Angeles], n.d.; 22 leaves. Typescript. (Box 22, Folder 3)
          Included are only the first 22pp.
        - The man who didn't go to Harvard. Bala, Pennsylvania, n.d.; 8 leaves. Typescript (carbon). (Box 22, Folder 3)
        - The radiant isle. n.p., n.d.; 6 leaves. Typescript. (Box 22, Folder 3)
        - The siamese cat. Bala, Pennsylvania., 15 leaves. Typescript (carbon). (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Perry, Emek - A place of judgement. Los Angeles, 1961.; 22 leaves. Typescript (carbon). (Box 22, Folder 4)
        Included are 2 leaves of correspondence.
      - Wilson, Charles Morrow - Ambassadors in white. New York, 1942.; 45 leaves. Typescript. (Box 22, Folder 5)
        This is a story treatment of a book.
        Also included are 1 letter and 8 ephemera.
- Involvement with Little Theatres, ca. 1920-1930
  - Material re the Partnership of Kenneth Macgowan and Joseph Verner Reed
    Known as: Macgowan and Reed, Incorporated.
    - Correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan, Joseph Verner Reed, and various persons re the partnership, Macgowan and Reed, Incorporated. v.p., 1930-1956.; 89 items. Holograph and typescript (some carbon). (Box 23, Folder 1)
      The bulk of the correspondence is between Mr. Macgowan and Mr. Reed. All items are arranged alphabetically.
      - Aldrich, Richard., 4 items. (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Dean, Basil., 7 items. (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Hayes, Helen., 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Krutch, Joseph Wood., 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Reed, Joseph Verner., 79 items. (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous material re the partnership Macgowan and Reed, Incorporated. v.p., v.d.; 88 items. Typescript (much carbon). (Box 23, Folder 2)
      Included are various notes, fragments, receipts, and financial statements re various productions and general business matters of the partnership.
    - Macgowan, Kenneth, 1888-1963. - Five little productions and how they grew. n.p., 1932.; 2 items. Typescript (mostly carbon), and printed material. (Box 23, Folder 3)
      Included are the manuscript and printed versions of the article, which tells of the productions of Macgowan and Reed, Incorporated.
    - Material re the Macgowan and Reed, Incorporated. Production of Art and Mrs. Bottle. v.p., 1930.; 12 items. (Box 23, Folder 4)
      Included are typescript quotes of comments about the production, clippings of reviews, and a telegram.
    - Material re the Macgowan and Reed, Incorporated. Production of Autumn Crocus. v.p., 1931-1932.; 23 items. Holograph and printed. (Box 23, Folder 5)
      Included are a few miscellaneous letters re the production, and many clippings of reviews and comments concerning the production.
    - Material re the Macgowan and Reed, Incorporated. Production of Children of Darkness. v.p., 1930.; 34 items. Teletype, printed, and photograph. (Box 23, Folder 6)
      Included are sucess-wishing telegrams from David Belasco; Robert Bell; Irwin S. and Henry I. Chanin; Paul Foley; Dorothy Gish; Lucy Huffaker, and Eddy Goodman; Dr. and Mrs. Lief; Albert Lovejoy; James and Dorothy Rennie; Sidney Ross, Basil Sidney and Mary Ellis; and 2 unidentified. Also included are many clippings of reviews, program ephemera, and 6 glossy, black and white photographs of scenes from the production.
    - Reviews, clipped from newspapers and periodicals of the Macgowan and Reed, Incorporated. Production of The Curtain Falls. v.p., 1935.; 14 items. Printed material. (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Material re the Macgowan and Reed, Incorporated. production The Lady With A Lamp. New York, 1931.; 9 items. Printed and photograph. (Box 23, Folder 8)
      Included are clippings of reviews pasted on manilla sheets, 2 programs, and 1 glossy black and white photograph of Edith Evans as Florence Nightingale.
    - Material re the Macgowan and Reed, Incorporated. production Lean Harvest. v.p., 1931.; 11 items. Printed material. (Box 23, Folder 9)
      Included are clippings of reviews, theater programs, and one issue of the magazine Theater World, containing a 12pp. pictorial souvenir of Lean Harvest.
    - Photographs of scenes from the Macgowan and Reed, Incorporated. Production of Lean Harvest. New York, 1931.; 11 items. Glossy, black and white, size 8 × 10. (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Material re the Mcgowan and Reed, Incorporated. production Love Story. v.p., 1931.; Approximately 25 items. Holograph and typescript (much carbon), plus 1 printed notice. (Box 23, Folder 11)
      Included are mostly lists, notes, and fragments, plus 1 letter and clipping.
    - Reviews, clipped from newspapers, of the Macgowan and Reed, Incorporated. Production of The Marquis. v.p., 1927.; 5 items. Printed material. (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Material re the Macgowan and Reed, Incorporated. Production of Springtime For Henry. v.p., 1932.; Approximately 150 items. Holograph and typescript (much carbon), and some printed items. (Box 24, Folder 1)
      Included, primarily, are business correspondence re the production (chronologically arranged), various notes, and financial lists, plus a few clippings and theater programs.
    - Complete script, and some individual parts for the Macgowan and Reed, Incorporated. Production of Springtime For Henry. n.p., 1932.; 6 items. Typescript (some carbon). (Box 24, Folder 2)
      Included are parts for the characters Julia, Miss Jones, Jelliwell, Dewlip, and Miss Smith.
    - Photographs of scenes from the Macgowan and Reed, Incorporated. production Springtime For Henry. New York, 1932.; 10 items. Glossy, black and white, 8 × 10. (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Ephemera, mostly reviews, re the Macgowan and Reed, Incorporated. Production of Twelfth Night. v.p., 1930.; Approximately 50 items. Printed material. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Ephemera, announcements and theater programs for the Macgowan and Reed, Incorporated. Production of Twelfth Night, and for the star, Jane Cowl. New York, 1930.; 13 items. Printed material. (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Photographs of scenes from the Macgowan and Reed, Incorporated. Production of Twelfth Night. New York, 1930.; 22 items. Glossy, black and white. 8 × 10. (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Material re the Macgowan and Reed, Incorporated. Production of When Hell Froze. New York, 1930.; 7 items. Printed and photograph. (Box 24, Folder 7)
      Included are 5 photographs, black and white, size 8 × 10, plus 1 clipping, and 1 theater program.
    - Material re the Macgowan and Reed, Incorporated. Production of Young Love. v.p., 1927-1932.; Approximately 50 items. Typescript (much carbon). (Box 24, Folder 8)
      Included are miscellaneous business correspondence, and lists re the production, arranged in chronological order.
    - Financial statements and contractual agreements for the Macgowan and Reed, Incorporated. Production of Young Love. New York, 1927-1929.; 5 items. Typescript (some carbon). (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Ephemera re the Macgowan and Reed, Incorporated. Production of Young Love. v.p., 1928.; 47 items. Printed material. (Box 24, Folder 10)
      The items consist of newspaper clippings of reviews, notices, and theater programs.
    - Unidentified photographs of scenes from a Macgowan and Reed, Incorporated. production. n.p., 3 items. Black and white, 8 × 10. (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Material re the Greenwich Village Theatre, the Actors Theatre, the Experimental Theatre, and Other Little Theaters With Which Kenneth Macgowan Was Affiliated
    - Newspaper clippings, business correspondence, and miscellaneous papers re the Actors' Theatre and its merge with the Greenwich Village Theatre. New York, 1925-1927.; 30 items. Mostly typescript (much carbon), and some printed material. (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Ephemera re the Actors' Theatre production of God Loves Us. New York, 1926.; 20 items. Mostly printed material. (Box 25, Folder 2)
      Includes newspaper clippings of notices and reviews, 2 theater programs, and 1 letter.
    - Articles clipped from newspapers concerning Kenneth Macgowan's resignation as the director of The Actors' Theatre. New York, November 1926.; 11 items. Printed material. (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Financial statements and contractual agreements between the Greenwich Village Theatre and the Experimental Theatre, Incorporated. New York, 1922-1927.; 17 items. Typescript (much carbon). (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous material re the Greenwich Village Theatre. New York, 1925-1926.; 33 items. Holograph, typescript, mimeograph, and printed. (Box 25, Folder 5)
      Included are clippings, advertisements, programs, financial papers, notices, and miscellaneous letters and notes.
    - Ephemera re various little theater productions of Fashion, with which Kenneth Macgowan was involved. New York, 1924.; 30 items. Printed material, plus 1 typescript leaf of correspondence. (Box 25, Folder 6)
      Included are clippings, programs, notes, etc.
  - Material re the Provincetown Playhouse and Players, and Other Little Theaters
    - Correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan and various persons re the Provincetown Playhouse. New York, 1924-1925.; 24 items. Holograph and typescript (some carbon). (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Almy, Don R., 1 item. (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Eldridge, Florence., 1 item. (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Fitzgerald, Eleanor., 6 items. (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Keating, George., 1 item. (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Weinberger, Harry., 7 items. (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, fragments, etc. v.p., v.d.; 8 items. (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Material re the production of Outside Looking In written by Maxwell Anderson, as presented by Macgowan, Jones, and O'Neill. New York, 1925.; 28 items. Mostly printed ephemera. (Box 26, Folder 2)
      Including clippings, advertisements, theater programs, plus 1 list, and 2 typescript leaves of correspondence.
    - Material re the production of The Spook Sonata written by August Strindberg, as presented by Macgowan, Jones, and O'Neill. New York, 1924.; 35 items. (Box 26, Folder 3)
      Included are mostly printed ephemera, clippings, playbills, etc., plus 1 typescript leaf of notes.
    - Ephemera re the Provincetown Players, and the Provincetown Playhouse. New York, v.d.; 49 items. (Box 26, Folder 4)
      Includes photographs, advertisements, mailers, various printed information, and other material.
    - Ephemera re the Provincetown Players and the Provincetown Playhouse. New York, 1923-1930.; 14 items. Printed material. (Box 26, Folder 5)
      Includes clippings from newspapers and periodicals, chronologically arranged.
    - Playbills for the Provincetown Playhouse, and the Greenwich Village Theatre. New York, 1920-1930.; 36 items. Printed material, duplicates included. (Box 26, Folder 6)
      These playbills are valuable sources of information about little theater in the United States, and contain many articles, reviews and comments.
    - Miscellaneous financial and other records re various little theater productions Kenneth Macgowan was involved with. New York, 1923-1927.; Approximately 35 items. Manuscript and typescript (some carbon). (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Provincetown Playhouse agreements. New York, 1923.; 6 items. Typescript (much carbon), plus 1 photocopy. (Box 26, Folder 8)
      Included are 2 agreements; one forming the Provincetown Playhouse, (1 typescript plus 4 carbon copies), and one leaf, photocopy of the first page of the Certificate of Incorporation of the Provincetown Playhouse, corporate name to be the Experimental Theatre, Incorporated.
    - Miscellaneous material re the Provincetown Playhouse and Players, the Greenwich Village Theatre and the Experimental Theatre. [New York], 1923-1924.; Approximately 30 items. Manuscript, typescript (much carbon), and 1 printed item. (Box 26, Folder 9)
      Included are lists of questions and answers, various production lists, notes, financial information, and charts.
    - Miscellaneous lists of casts for variou productions. [New York, 1923-1930.; Approximately 20 items. Manuscript and typescript (carbon and mimeograph). (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Eulogy for Eleanor Fitzgerald, and a commemorative booklet about her. New York, 1955.; 4 items. Typescript (carbon), and printed material. (Box 26, Folder 11)
      The eulogy was published in the New York Times, April 10, 1955. A clipping of it is included.
    - Quotations from scripts of various productions, and quotations from reviews of various productions. New York [?], 1920-1930.; 46 leaves. Typescript (mostly carbon). (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Material re Eugene O'Neill
    - Printed articles about Eugene O'Neill, as clipped from various periodicals. v.p., ca. 1920-1940.; 9 items. Chronologically arranged. (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Various articles about Eugene O'Neill. n.p., n.d.; 5 items. Typescript. (Box 27, Folder 2)
      3 copies of 1 article, another article, and notes.
    - An open letter to Eugene O'Neill. Los Angeles, 1940.; 3 items. 1 typescript, and 2 printed copies. (Box 27, Folder 3)
      This article was published in the Los Angeles Times, Thursday, December 12, 1940, Part 1, p.17.
    - O'Neill and a mature Hollywood outlook. Los Angeles, 1958.; 3 items. 1 typescript and 2 printed copies. (Box 27, Folder 4)
      This article was published in Theatre Arts (April 1958), pp.79-81.
    - Material re Kenneth Macgowan's lectures on Eugene O'Neill. v.p., 1928-1961.; Approximately 50 items. Typescript (some carbon) and printed. (Box 27, Folder 5)